OLENA YATSENKO



CONTACT

Address:

Lisbon, Portugal

Phone/Telegram:

- +380 930 505 022
- +351 914 016 748

Email:

chaplinalena@gmail.com

Linkedin:

https://www.linkedin.com/in/olena-yatsenko/

LANGUAGES

English — Upper-Intermediate

Portuguese — Elementary

SUMMARY STATEMENT

Meticulous Business Analyst with 3 years of experience in working with requirements elicitation, analysis and documentation within an Agile methodology framework.

History of assisting companies of different domains, such as medical hightech project intended to assist surgeons with pre-operative planning and fintech project that delivers asset data management powered by blockchain. Having experience also as a team leader, passionate and proficient about communication, solving industry problems and dependencies as well as decision making.

WORK EXPERIENCE

01/2022 - 11/2022

Company: Dev.Pro\Inveniam, Portugal Lisbon Middle Business Analyst

information archived within the Inveniam.io system

Dev.Pro is a US-based outsource company of people who value high ethical standards and have delivered superior software products since 2011. **Project:** Blockchain web project. The platform keeps a comprehensive record of all activity within the system, recording milestone events, transaction artifacts, and user interactions on the Ethereum distributed

ledger as a series of blockchain transactions that are immutably linked to

Responsibilities:

- Work with product managers and other stakeholders in terms of business needs, requirements, functionality and improvement opportunities;
- Elicitation, analysis and documentation of software requirements into detailed specifications in the form of user stories and acceptance criteria;
- Stakeholders representation for the development team and assistance with clarification of the clients' requirements;
- Management of changes requested by stakeholders in tight collaboration with the product manager and developers
- Identification and resolution of issues with conflicting requirements;
- Presentation of Sprint results for stakeholders within Demo
- Facilitation of Agile ceremonies (dailys, planning, grooming, review)

07/2014 – 12/2021

Company: Materialise, Kyiv Ukraine

Materialise is a dynamic international high-tech company, founded in 1990 and headquartered in Belgium, with over 2,100 employees worldwide. Materialise's mission is to innovate for a better and healthier world through its software and hardware infrastructure and in-depth knowledge of additive manufacturing (also known as 3D Printing). Customers are in diverse industries, such as automotive, aerospace, medical, research and academia.

Functional/system analyst

Project: SurgiCase Shoulder Planner is intended to be used as a pre-surgical planner for simulation of surgical interventions for shoulder orthopedic surgery. The software is used to assist in the positioning of shoulder components. SurgiCase Shoulder Planner allows the surgeon to visualize, measure, reconstruct, annotate and edit pre-surgical plan data. The software leads to the generation of a surgery report along with a pre-surgical plan data file which can be used as input data to design the Materialise Shoulder Guide and Models

Responsibilities:

- Requirements elicitation and ideation on solutions in close collaboration with project stakeholders;
- Functional and non-functional requirements elicitation and development;
- Documentation and managing requirements according to medical regulations;
- Holding Grooming sessions with the development team. Consult development/test teams during the implementation phase;
- Analysis and design of business processes;
- Requirements and changes management;
- Test scenarios review;
- Product testing participating;
- Application quality improvement;
- Synchronization/ negotiation with other development teams regarding integration;
- Stakeholders management.

08/2018 - 04/2020

Team Leader

Responsibilities:

- Set clear team and personal goals and KPIs linked to the corporate and department goals
- Involve team to the long-term project vision & strategy building
- Involve team to the project related decision making
- Keep people engaged and informed about product/project plans & changes
- Create a healthy and motivating work environment and atmosphere
- Encourage initiatives and new ideas team-members bring to the table

02/2017 - 08/2018

Expert Trainer

Responsibilities:

- Preparation and providing trainings within the agreed time period and target KPIs
- Quality documentation (SUGs, REAs)
- Shorter term of trainings with good quality-case time results

• Developing co-coaching program: right people for the right tasks

07/2014 - 02/2017

Medical Engineer

Responsibilities:

- Provide virtual preliminary surgery planning based on 3D objects
- Design patient-specific medical devices and tools considering customer's requirements

09/2013 - 06/2014

Company: VIDEOPROBKI

Content Manager

03/2011 - 09/2013

Company: Mapia Content Manager

EDUCATION

09/2005 - 08/2011

Master Degree of Applied Statistics, Faculty of Cybernetics, Shevchenko Kyiv National University